polaroidoriginals.com 2019-09-21

# Privacy policy

**Privacy Policy and Newsletter Privacy Policy**

Impossible B.V. ("Impossible" or "we") is committed to respecting the privacy rights of visitors to its website. This Privacy Policy ("Privacy Policy") explains how we collect, store, and use personal data about you when you browse www.polaroidoriginals.com (the "Website"), shop with us or otherwise provide your personal data to us. This Privacy Policy applies regardless of how the Website is accessed and will cover any technologies or devices by which Impossible makes the Website available to you. Please read this Privacy Policy carefully as by accessing, browsing or otherwise using this Website you confirm that you have read and understood this Privacy Policy. We only process your data based on a legal basis in compliance with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and other applicable laws regarding the protection of personal data. Whenever the processing of personal data is based on your given consent, you are free to withdraw your consent if you don’t want us to process your personal data anymore. We may have to change this Privacy Policy from time to time. You’ll find the most recent version of this Privacy Policy on our website.

**1\. Who we are**

Impossible B.V. is a company registered with the commercial register for Oost Nederland in The Netherlands (registration number 08182413) whose registered office is at Hoge Bothofstraat 45, 7511 ZA Enschede, The Netherlands (PO Box 242, 7500 AE Enschede, The Netherlands). Impossible is part of the Impossible group of companies.

We respect your right to privacy and will only process personal data you provide to us in accordance with the General Data Protection Regulation 2016/679/EU and applicable national data protection legislation, as updated from time to time.

**2\. The personal data we collect about you**

When you purchase from Impossible through the Website (including purchases made on any device) we and/or our third party data processors acting on our behalf may collect the following personal data about you:

your (sur)name;   
your billing and delivery postal addresses, phone (including mobile phone) and email details;   
your user name and password;   
your IP address;   
where you have registered with us;   
where you place an order with us;   
your communication and shopping preferences;     
your browsing and online shopping activities;   
any company name if you choose to provide us with this information.

We may also collect some or all of the above personal data about you when you access and browse this Website.   
We may also collect some or all of this personal data from third parties who have your consent to pass your details to us. This is the case with e-mail addresses you fill in using forms on other websites and Predicted Demographics data provided by MailChimp and/or other service providers, regarding your name, e-mail address and eligible use instances of social media tools in the context of our loyalty program (for more information we refer to paragraph 3.2). This is also the case regarding unique visitor identifiers as assigned by Facebook and Google through usage of “Facebook Pixel” and “Google Analytics” (we refer to paragraph 3.3).

We may ask you to provide a credit card number or other payment service details when making a purchase, however all credit card numbers or other payment service details you provide through on the Website are processed and/or stored by a third party credit card or payment facilitator or processor, and not by us.

**2.1 Legal bases of the processing of your personal data**

We only process your personal data when we have a legal base to do so, in accordance with Article 6 GDPR. 

We mainly process your personal data because this is strictly necessary for the performance of an agreement or contract made with you, i.e. to deliver your order to you, or to enable you to browse our website. If the personal data required in this context is not provided, this may have consequences for the possibilities with regards to purchases or delivery, or your possibilities in using our website.

We also process certain personal data after you have granted free, specific, informed and unambiguous consent in this regard. You are entitled at any time to withdraw your permission for these certain processing of personal data. This does not, however, affect the lawfulness of the processing on the basis of this consent prior to the withdrawal thereof.

We also process some personal data because this is necessary for the purposes of legitimate interests, which include fraud prevention and combating by Impossible (which are, in those specific cases, not overridden by your privacy interests). We refer to paragraph 3.5 for more information on our fraud prevention measures. We also process some personal data because it is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which Impossible is subject. If you don’t provide us with the concerned personal data, this may influence our possibilities to offer and provide our services and products to you.

**3\. How we may store and use your information**

Impossible (and third party data processors acting on our behalf) may collect, store and process your personal data for the following purposes:

to make this Website available to you and to provide you with content which is tailored to your individual tastes;   
to maintain any registered account that you hold with us;   
with your agreement, to contact you (including by push notifications and email) about promotional offers and products and services which we think may interest you;   
for customer satisfaction and market research purposes;   
to provide our goods and services to you and for associate purposes, including verifying your identity;   
to keep your order(s) in your shopping cart so you can get back to it later;   
for research, analysis, testing, monitoring, risk management, and administrative purposes;   
to enable you to take part in our loyalty programme; and   
for fraud prevention, fraud combating and related anti-fraud measures, as well as to comply with legal duties imposed on Impossible or legal duty to use or disclose your information.   
In addition, we may collect pseudonymised details about visitors to our Website for the purposes of aggregate statistics or reporting purposes.  However, no single individual will be identifiable from the pseudonymised details we collect for these purposes.

We will not disclose, sell, trade, or rent your personal data to any third party, save for any disclosures of your personal data detailed in this Privacy Policy.

In the event that a third party acquires all or part of our business and/or assets, we may disclose your personal data to that third party in connection with the acquisition. Furthermore, we reserve the right to disclose your personal data to third parties as part of any business or asset sale carried out because Impossible has gone into insolvency or any similar situation, but only where lawful and compliant with the applicable data protection legislation, as amended from time to time. We may also disclose your personal data where necessary to comply with applicable law or an order of a governmental or law enforcement body.  

**3.1. Email newsletter**

For email newsletters please refer to our Newsletter Privacy Policy.

**3.2. Loyalty program**

When ordering products on the Website you automatically enrol in a loyalty program facilitated by a third party. For this purpose, encrypted personal data and encrypted data regarding your order such as order value and potential discounts are transferred to and stored by such third party and will only be used to perform its services in connection with the loyalty program.

**3.3. Cookies and comparable technologies**

Impossible uses essential, analytics and tracking cookies on the Website, as well as comparable technologies.

Certain cookies and technologies are essential in order for the Website to operate. These are necessary for us to provide the basic functionalities of the Website. We will use these essential cookies and technologies also without obtaining your consent   
Apart from the essential cookies, we will only use analytics and tracking cookies and comparable technologies after you have granted free, specific, informed and unambiguous consent for this. You provide us with your consent for the use of analytics and tracking cookies when you choose the cookie settings upon entering our website. You are entitled at any time to withdraw or change your consent for our usage of these analytic and tracking cookies and comparable technologies. This does not, however, affect the lawfulness of the processing on the basis of this consent prior to the withdrawal thereof. If you were to withdraw your consent for the usage of the analytic and tracking cookies and comparable technologies, it will prevent us from personalizing our site for your convenience and showing you relevant content, including but not limited to personalized offers, discounts, or advertisements.

If you browse this Website, you may receive personalised banner advertisements whilst browsing other reputable websites. We are committed to providing you with information on products and offers which are relevant to you. When you visit other websites, you may see an advertisement for our products because you visited this Website. This is possible due to our usage of Google Analytics, Google Analytics for Display Advertising and AdWords Remarketing and/or similar services.

This Website uses Google Analytics, Google Analytics for Display Advertising and AdWords Remarketing and web analytics services provided by Google Inc. ("Google"). The information generated by the cookies will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States of America. Google will use this information on Impossible's behalf for the purpose of evaluating your use of the Website, compiling reports on Website activity for us and providing Impossible other services relating to website activity and internet usage. The IP address that your website browser conveys within the scope of Google Analytics, Google Analytics for Display Advertising and/or AdWords Remarketing will not be associated with any other data held by Google. The privacy policy for these Google services can be found under https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/. 

Social Networks   
Some pages on the Website load information from social networks to enable targeted advertising for our products on the social network platform which is activated every time someone opens a web page where a certain code is installed. This piece of code sends such general hashed information about the actions people take on a website to the social networks to help the website provider to target its advertisements to the people who took an action on its website. Facebook provides us with this information through ‘Facebook Pixel’.

Retargeting   
This Website uses a retargeting technology which uses cookies.

Live support system   
This Website collects and stores pseudonymized data to operate a live chat system to answer live support inquiries which uses cookies.

Web beacons and flash cookies   
We and/or third party data processors acting on our behalf may also use web beacons and flash cookies. Web beacons are embedded in a website or email and allow to check if a user has accessed certain content of such website or email. Flash cookies are pieces of data that websites which use Adobe Flash may store on a user's computer and can be used to store user preferences, save data from flash games, or to track a user's internet activity.

For more information, or to change or withdraw your cookie consent settings, see our cookies page at https://polaroidoriginals.com/pages/cookies

**3.4. International transfers**

We may transfer personal data that we collect from you to third party data processors located in countries that are outside of the European Economic Area and to other Impossible group companies in connection with the above purposes. These countries are either listed under the EU-US Privacy Shield, the European Commission has taken an adequacy decision regarding these countries or parties or they have taken appropriate or suitable safeguards.

**3.5 Fraud prevention**

In regard to fraud prevention and combatting, we use services which, among others, help us to determine whether or not a transaction should be made (should there be any doubt).

For this purpose, we share certain personal information with third parties who help us to detect and prevent fraudulent transactions. The information we share with those third parties includes some of the information that you share with us (such as, your contact details and information about the transaction), and some of the information from your online interactions (such as the IP address of your device). That information is used to determine whether a transaction could be fraudulent. One of the third parties we use to help us detect and prevent fraudulent transactions is a company called Signifyd; they are responsible for their use of your personal information and will use it for the purposes set out in their privacy policy (https://www.signifyd.com/privacy/).

**3.6 Our processors and other recipients**

Only those employees of Impossible whose access to the personal data is necessary will have access to it. Our employees, as well as the third parties to whom personal data is made available, are obliged to respect the confidentiality of your personal data. We also impose this obligation on processors through a data processing agreement that we use when executing our services.

Impossible does not in principle provide your personal data to third parties, unless this is necessary for the aforementioned purposes. In that context, Impossible will provide your personal data to parties who facilitate order placement and payment, payment guarantees and authorisation, fraud prevention and browser session monitoring. In addition, Impossible will make personal data available to third parties if a legal obligation or a court order requires it to do so.

**4\. Security**

We use internet standard encryption technology ("SSL" or "Secure Socket Layer" technology) to encode personal data that you send to us when placing an order through the Website. To check that you are in a secure area of the Website before sending personal data to us, please check that your website browser displays an image of a closed padlock or an unbroken key at the beginning of the website address.

However, please note that whilst we take appropriate technical and organisational measures to safeguard the personal data that you provide to us, no transmission over the internet can ever be guaranteed secure.  Consequently, please note that we cannot guarantee the security of any personal data that you transfer via the internet to us.

**5\. Spoof/false emails**

We will never ask you to confirm any account or credit card details via email. If you receive an email claiming to be from us asking you to do so, please ignore it and do not respond. You may forward any such e-mail to service@polaroidoriginals.com.

**6\. Your rights**

You have the following rights:

the right to ask what personal data we hold about you at any time and obtain information in that regard;   
the right to ask us to update and correct any out-of-date or incorrect personal data that we hold about you free of charge;   
the right to erasure of your personal data (under circumstances listed in the applicable law);   
the right to restrict the processing of your personal data (under circumstances listed in the applicable law);   
the right to object against the processing of your personal data;   
the right to data portability (you can ask us to provide you or a third party with your personal data in a readable and accessible form); and   
the right to opt out of any marketing communications.

For security purposes we may occasionally request proof of identity before we are able to disclose personal information to you. If you wish to exercise any of the above rights, please contact us using the contact details specified above.  However, if you wish to unsubscribe from email marketing communications that we send you, you can most easily do this by clicking on the unsubscribe link at the bottom of any e-mail marketing communications that we have sent to you.

**7\. Data retention**

Impossible will not retain the personal data for longer than is necessary for the purposes for which it is collected or processed. Impossible will in any case comply with legal data retention obligations.

**8\. Third party sites**

This Website contains links to other websites operated by third parties.  Please note that this Privacy Policy applies only to the personal data that we collect through this Website and we are not responsible for personal data that third parties may collect, store, and use through their websites. We recommend that you check the privacy policies of such other websites.

We do not exercise control over the websites that may be linked to the Website. These other websites may place their own cookies or other files on your computer, collect data, or solicit personal information from you.

**9\. Updates to this Privacy Policy**

This Privacy Policy was last updated in February 2019. Please check back regularly to stay informed of updates to this Privacy Policy.

In case you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or your personal experience dealing with the Website please contact us on service@polaroidoriginals.com.

In case you would like to exercise your rights as stated in Paragraph 6, please contact us on service@polaroidoriginals.com.

**10\. Complaints**

If you are of the opinion that Impossible processes your personal data in an improper or unlawful manner and that Impossible does not / insufficiently heed your objection or other submitted request in the context of your already described rights, or you have other reasons for submitting a complaint in the context of the processing of your personal data, you can at all times submit a complaint to the Data Protection Authority.

* * *

**Newsletter Privacy Policy**

Impossible B.V. (“Impossible” or “we”) is committed to respecting your privacy rights. This Newsletter Privacy Policy explains how we collect, store and use your personal data when you subscribe to our email newsletter. Please read this Newsletter Privacy Policy carefully as by accessing, browsing or otherwise using this Website you confirm that you have read and understood this Newsletter Privacy Policy. 

We only process your data based on a legal basis in compliance with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and other applicable laws. If you don’t want us to process your personal data anymore then you are free to withdraw your consent at any moment by clicking the ‘unsubscribe’ link or by contacting us at service@polaroidoriginals.com. You will find an ‘unsubscribe’ link at the bottom of any email newsletter we have sent to you.

We may have to change this Newsletter Privacy Policy from time to time. You’ll find the most recent version of this Newsletter Privacy Policy on our website. .

**1\. Who we are**

Impossible B.V. is a company registered with the commercial register for Oost Nederland in The Netherlands (registration number 08182413) whose registered office is at Hoge Bothofstraat 45, 7511 ZA Enschede, The Netherlands (PO Box 242, 7500 AE Enschede, The Netherlands). Impossible is part of the Impossible group of companies.

We respect your right to privacy and will only process personal data you provide to us in accordance with the General Data Protection Regulation (EU) 2016/679 and applicable national data protection legislation, as updated from time to time.

**2\. The personal data we collect about you**

Impossible will collect personal data in case you subscribe to the email newsletter and agree with our Newsletter Privacy Policy. For the purpose of sending you our email newsletters we process your email address, as well as data obtained from public sources by MailChimp (these may include age group and geographic location). This data will be processed by MailChimp. You can find MailChimp's Privacy Policy under https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/, and their Terms under https://mailchimp.com/legal/terms/. Such data will be used for our own advertising purposes.

**3\. Legal bases of the processing of your personal data**

We only process your personal data when we have a legal basis to do so, in accordance with Article 6 GDPR. The legal basis with respect to our email newsletters is consent. That means that we only process your personal data after you have given us free, specific, informed and unambiguous consent. You can withdraw your permission for the processing of personal data at any moment by clicking the ‘unsubscribe’ link at the bottom of any email newsletter we have sent to you. If you withdraw your permission, we may no longer be able to send you our newsletters. Please be aware that withdrawing your permission does not affect the legality of the processing of your personal data prior to your withdrawal.

Furthermore, you can control whether or not you wish to receive email newsletters through MailChimp's newsletter preference centre. You can find this preference centre by clicking https://goo.gl/Tw9XM8. Once we have processed your opt-out request we will not send you newsletters unless you opt back into receiving such communications.

**4\. How we may store and use your personal data**

Your personal data will be stored by us up to the moment that:

you let us know that you want to withdraw your consent;   
we stop sending our email newsletters;   
your email address is no longer in use.

**5\. With whom we may share your personal data**

In order to be able to send you our email newsletters, some of our employees may have access to your personal data. The group of employees with access to your data is limited to those whose access is strictly necessary to ensure you can receive our email newsletters.

Our employees, as well as the third parties to whom the personal data is made available, are obliged to respect the confidentiality of your personal data. By means of a data processing agreement we impose restrictions on third parties with regard to the use of your personal data and impose obligations on third parties with respect to the protection and security of your personal data.

In order to be able to send you our email newsletters, we may also transfer your personal data to third party data processors located outside of the European Economic Area. In such a case, we ensure that measures are taken so that your personal data is adequately protected. This means that the third party is either listed under the EU-US Privacy Shield, that the European Commission has taken adequacy decision on the level of protection in that third country or that the third party has itself taken appropriate and suitable safeguards.

To make sure our email newsletter is sent to you, we share your personal data with MailChimp (The Rocket Science Group, LLC). Mailchimp is listed under the EU-US Privacy Shield.

**6\. Your rights**

You have the following rights:

the right to ask what personal data we hold about you at any time and obtain information in that regard;   
the right to ask us to update and correct any out-of-date or incorrect personal data that we hold about you free of charge;   
the right to erasure of your personal data (under circumstances listed in the applicable law);   
the right to restrict the processing of your personal data (under circumstances listed in the applicable law);   
the right to object against the processing of your personal data;   
the right to data portability (you can ask us to provide you or a third party with your personal data in a readable and accessible form); and   
the right to unsubscribe from the email newsletter by clicking the ‘unsubscribe’ link at the bottom of any email newsletter we send you;

If you wish to exercise any of the above rights, please contact us using the contact details specified above. 

**7\. Updates to this Newsletter Privacy Policy**

This Newsletter Privacy Policy was last updated in February 2019. Please check back regularly to stay informed of updates to this Newsletter Privacy Policy.   
In case you have any questions about this Newsletter Privacy Policy or if you would like to exercise any of your rights in Paragraph 6, please contact us on service@polaroidoriginals.com.

**8\. Complaints**

If you are of the opinion that we process your personal data in an improper or unlawful manner, that we do not / insufficiently take regard of your objection or request in the context of your rights or if you wish to make a complaint in the context of the processing of your personal data, you have at all times the right to lodge a complaint with the Data Protection Authority.
